<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<sections title="Eclipse Persistence Services Project: EclipseLink">
	<section class="main" name="About EclipseLink">
		<description>
			The Eclipse Persistence Services Project (EclipseLink)
			incubator project's goal is to provide an extensible
			framework that will enable Java developers to interact with
			relational databases, XML, and Enterprise Information
			Systems (EIS) in an efficient and productive manor.
			EclipseLink will focus on supporting leading persistence
			standards including the Java Persistence API (JPA), Java API
			for XML Binding (JAXB), Java Connector Architecture (JCA),
			and Service Data Objects (SDO).
		</description>
	</section>
	<section class="main" name="Project Organization">
		<description>
			<p>
				The Eclipse Persistence Services Project is a
				sub-project of the Technology project. This Project will
				provide persistence services in an extensible framework
				focusing on performance, productivity, and flexibility.
				The following services and functional areas are defined
				to be in the initial scope of this project:
			</p>
			<p>
				<b>JPA</b>
			</p>
			<p>
				The JPA service supports the Java Persistence API (JPA)
				and enables mapping a Java domain model to a relational
				schema using metadata provided in XML and/or
				annotations. Applications using this service will have
				access to the mapping, query framework, transaction
				support, object caching (including clustering support),
				advanced database specific capabilities, and many
				performance tuning and management options. Each of these
				functional areas are flexible and extensible to address
				complex application requirements.
			</p>
			<p>
				<b>Mapping Objects to XML (MOXy)</b>
			</p>
			<p>
				The Mapping Objects to XML (MOXy) service with support
				for Java Architecture for XML Binding (JAXB) enables
				mapping of a Java domain model to an XML Schema (XSD)
				using metadata provided in XML and/or annotations. This
				service supports the generation of mappings and XSD from
				an annotated model, generation of the domain model and
				mapping from a provided XSD, or meet-in-the-middle
				mapping with a provided domain model and XSD. The
				application interface enables the efficient marshalling
				of the domain model objects into an XML document and
				un-marshalling of XML documents into domain model
				objects via DOM or SAX.
			</p>
			<p>
				<b>Service Data Object (SDO)</b>
			</p>
			<p>
				The Service Data Object (SDO) service will allow
				developers to generate dynamic and static SDO models
				from an XSD and use these within their application. In
				addition to the XML binding capabilities defined in the
				specification additional flexibility is provided by the
				Object-XML service. This approach provides a solution
				for applications requiring less coupling to the data
				structures being accessed and modified. Support for
				wrapping a Java object (i.e. JPA entity) within a
				DataObject will be provided to enable the usage of
				existing domain models with SDO.
			</p>
			<p>
				<b>Database Web Services (DBWS)</b>
			</p>
			<p>
				This service will provide a simple and declarative
				solution for defining and generating a Web service
				exposing database operations. Using the core
				Object-Relational and Object-XML capabilities, consumers
				can leverage default XML representations of their
				relational data or completely customize the shape of
				their XML documents.
			</p>
			<p>
				<b>Enterprise Information Systems (EIS)</b>
			</p>
			<p>
				The EIS persistence service enables the usage of data
				stores through Java Connector Architecture (JCA)
				resource adapters. Using XML metadata the interactions
				and their exchanged data are configured and mapped onto
				a domain model. The interactions data can be mapped from
				either the Common Client interface (CCI) or using XML
				schemas. This usage is intended for non-relational data
				stores where no JDBC or SQL access is provided.
			</p>
			<img src="images/EclipseLink-overview.png" border="0" />
		</description>
	</section>
	<section class="infobox" name="Incubation">
		<description>
			<div align="center">
				<a href="/projects/what-is-incubation.php">
					<img align="center" src="/images/egg-incubation.png"
						border="0" />
				</a>
			</div>
			<div align="center">
				This project is in the
				<a href="/projects/dev_process/validation-phase.php">
					Incubation Phase
				</a>
			</div>
		</description>
	</section>
	<section class="infobox" name="Learn More">
		<item title="Project News" link="#ProjectNews" />
		<item title="Newsgroup"
			link="http://www.eclipse.org/newsportal/thread.php?group=eclipse.technology.eclipselink">
			<a href="http://www.eclipse.org/newsgroups/index.html"
				target="_blank">
				[sign up]
			</a>
		</item>
		<item title="EclipseLink Wiki"
			link="http://wiki.eclipse.org/EclipseLink">
		</item>
		<item title="Original EclipseLink Proposal"
			link="http://www.eclipse.org/proposals/eclipselink/" />
		<item title="Creation Review Slides"
			link="http://www.eclipse.org/proposals/eclipselink/Eclipse_Persistence_Services-creation.pdf" />
	</section>
	<section class="infobox" name="Project News">
		<section name="EclipseLink @ Conferences" link="http://wiki.eclipse.org/EclipseLink/Presentations">
			<em>October 2007</em>
		</section>
		<section name="EclipseLink Provisioned">
			<em>June 2007</em>
		</section>
	</section>
</sections>
