<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<sections title="EclipseLink SDO">
	<section class="none" name="About EclipseLink SDO">
		<description>
			<p align="justify">
				EclipseLink SDO delivers a compliant SDO 2.1.1
				implementation...
			</p>
			<p align="justify">
				Service Data Objects (SDO) is designed to simplify and
				unify the way in which applications handle data. Using
				SDO, application programmers can uniformly access and
				manipulate data from heterogeneous data sources,
				including relational databases, XML data sources, Web
				services, and enterprise information systems.
			</p>
			<p align="justify">
				SDO is based on the concept of disconnected data graphs.
				A data graph is a collection of tree-structured or
				graph-structured data objects. Under the disconnected
				data graphs architecture, a client retrieves a data
				graph from a data source, mutates the data graph, and
				can then apply the data graph changes back to the data
				source.
			</p>
			<p align="justify">
				The task of connecting applications to data sources is
				performed by data mediator services. Client applications
				query a data mediator service and get a data graph in
				response. Client applications send an updated data graph
				to a data mediator service to have the updates applied
				to the original data source. This architecture allows
				applications to deal principally with data graphs and
				data objects.
			</p>
			<p align="justify">
				SDO enables both a static (or strongly typed)
				programming model and a dynamic (or loosely typed)
				programming model. This enables a simple programming
				model without sacrificing the dynamic model needed by
				tools and frameworks.
			</p>
			<p align="justify">
				SDO also provides a metadata API, which allows
				applications, tools, and frameworks to introspect the
				data model for a data graph. The SDO metadata API
				unifies data-source-specific metadata APIs to enable
				applications to handle data from heterogeneous data
				sources in a uniform way.
			</p>
			<p align="justify">
				SDO is intended to be language-neutral and to be
				available in a range of programming languages.
			</p>
		</description>
	</section>
</sections>
